How a bowling alley works.
First, the player rolls the ball down the lane.
Toward the end of the lane, it breaks an
infrared sensor, which initiates the pinsetter control unit.
Whoa!
It looks like our computer has crashed.
We'll have her back up and running in no time!
Okay. It looks like we're back online.
"Windows XP Boot Sound"
After the ball breaks the infrared sensor, it
finishes by knocking down a number of pins.
The sweep is lowered to protect the pinsetter from any late arriving balls.
A scanner camera snaps a photo to see
which pins are standing and which are knocked over.
This information is sent to the automatic scoring system.
The photo also lets the pinsetter know which pins it will need to pick up.
The sweep pushes any remaining pins into the ball pit.
And the standing pins are replaced onto the deck, and ready for the next round.
A conveyor belt in the ball pit moves the pins under a divider.
The ball however, is too large to fit under the divider
and therefore rolls into a hole
and out of the ball pit.
Another conveyor belt accelerates the ball up a ramp, and is returned to the player using gravity
by way of a track system under the alley.
While the ball is being returned, the
pins fall into a pin elevator wheel
and are brought up to another conveyor belt that transports them to the pin distributor.
Once all the pins have been loaded into
the distributor and the player has
rolled the second ball, the pins are
dropped into the pin table which lowers
down at the start of the next player's
round.
Created by Matt Rittman
Logo & Scorecard Design by Jordan Miller
Special thanks to 3DKiwi